uh here's a quick video about a very
common shell check error using a really
common technique for uh truncating a
file so the first question I have pause
the video see if you know the answer so
what does this do there's a there's a
greater than sign there and it's
pointing to Tempa right what does that
do um what this does is people people
look at this I've had people open issues
on my DOT files on this program by the
way on my y program because they have no
idea that I'm using it as filter command
from VII they're like you shouldn't be
doing that t does the same
thing I'm like okay and the truth is I
could I could replace this with t but
then I would have a subshell I don't
want a subshell I want this thing to run
without any subshell dependencies
because I do it all the time that's why
it's that way in fact I should probably
write that at some point in there so I
don't get another issue in my own dot
files by the way who does that so um
you're doing this wrong this is done in
the T command twitch bot hey life coding
what's up so so here we go we've got so
here's the co thing
uh so I have I have a redirect attemp up
and it tells me right here this
redirection does more and it's using the
Shell check ler in Al stay tuned watch
another video about that or join my live
stream anytime I'll come and do that we
doing right now we're doing terminal
tweaks and and fighting about all kinds
of things uh it's really fun though so
and this is just a regular little bin b
b bsh but to prove that this is also a
problem in bashor you go it it it's a
problem everywhere right so you need a
command here and there's no less than
like five ways to accomplish the same
thing could I do this I could do RM SL
10 buff for sure I could do that if it
didn't exist but then I would have to
redirect standard error if it doesn't
exist I don't think RM is silent I don't
know you know a little bit of it I mean
I want something easy this is something
I also do in the command line all the
time um another thing you could do is
you could put a command here so shell
check is actually recommending you put
true here
to do the thing but I want to show you
the most powerful
technique uh for doing things that do
not have a command that is possible in
Shell that's been supported since the
very dawn of time this is present in so
many Advanced uh shell scripts where
people who've been around the block a
lot so so pay attention because you're
about to learn a very Advanced but very
simple technique for Shell uh that will
make you look
cool like that we saw Guardians of the
Galaxy 3 the other night it's my
favorite Marvel Marvel movie and they
like did that look
cool there you go that's it that's it so
the a lot of people don't know that
colon is a command in all shells since
the beginning of time and so this is a
great way to say hey I want to do
something that I would normally do from
the shell that that does not have a
command that fixes it uh you might be
asking well what that's kind of stupid
why would you do that and you know
because it's easy to do you don't need
it on the command line when you're just
doing doing things but but let me show
you something else so if you CD to to
install um to install buntu you can use
this technique um actually let me go
back to my Kate's app uh bu is it over
here did I not have it Oh wait we're on
a Bastion let's go on Bastion let me
find
Bastion let's go back oh wait let's do
this it's a un system
all right let's go to Bastion we're
doing stuff here so I'm trying to okay
here we go so CD cadap haror and so here
I have a build script that uses this
technique uh for something that's much
more valuable this this is one of the
most I I absolutely love this technique
this is a a really common shell
technique for saying for making this
this is an argument destroyer and I mean
like argument it's like I absolutely
hate passing and parsing arguments in my
shell scripts I hate it and so does my
team my team has hated it too so we have
started doing this in fact I showed
somebody this and then I end end up
showing up as as part of our standard
specification for Kates apps and what
this does is it says hey I have this
thing here there's anytime you have some
fanciness like in this case bash um is
it's setting up what the default
arguments are right and so yeah I can
make a whole video just on default
arguments bash notice how they're all
caps separate video about that all caps
means it comes from the outside
environment um this allows you to
overwrite it even though these are these
are already hardcoded as as uh lowercase
in our system so so those have to be but
this means that this is just a really
great thing to put at the beginning of
your shell script and say I want to
allow my behavior to be changed by
changing the environment and if you work
with containers you know how that works
uh but I also want to set a default so
you set the default here that fults are
all really well declared and this any of
these things was what Shel would
immediately scream at me uh if it were
working it's not because it's not on
here right now
no yeah I'll fix that I I there's a
there's a bug watch my I have another
video about why this is
broken uh mostly because shell check is
not checking my stuff right now yeah
it's not it's
not it's it's it's not I'm going to show
you the other one so you can get can see
shell check complain
um Kate's oh we don't have it clone
Kate's
app my clone is a function it has to be
a function because it changes
directories which you have to do in a
function not a command because it's it's
a persistent thing Kate's app
Harbor okay let me clone this
thing okay so now we're in the harbor
thing so now now we're in the same place
we were before just on a different
machine now I'm back on my Mac my Unix
system um or am I oh wait
wait uh
switch
modernize all right so build all right
so here it is but I want to show you
hopefully sh Che will yell at
me no it didn't it's supposed to yell at
me why is it not yelling at
me why is it not yelling on me anyway
that was I was doing it we found it on
the redirection thing let me do just
show check I'm sort of intrigued by this
now what shell check doesn't catch
that that's super fascinating I did not
know that but you should do it anyway
you should do it you should do that
anyway it's an it's a it's an empty
command and then you know
what I wonder if it's a a shell
thing what the hell
I could have swore that was a shell
check thing I can't believe that's
passing shell check right now it
isn't other stuff is also not passing it
so this is actually a different problem
yeah which we're going to fix right now
this is because yeah here we go so now
now she'll checks finding all kinds of
stuff all right so there's another video
about how to fix that to get that to
work um and clearly it's uh it hasn't
been fixed yet on here I'm going to do
that but um so there you go that that
shows you uh the stuff so if I change
this back to
bash yeah it's fine
interesting this is all see all these
things this these are all problems
because the syntax is wrong for this
particular thing now because you see the
type down here is s it's a separate
issue anyway this video is about the
colon command and how you can use that
to do redirection so I'll end the video
there